http://www.thesnellgroup.com/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
HomeInfrared Training Infrared CoursesInfrared Training ScheduleLive IR Webcasts & On-Demand WebinarsOnline Infrared CoursesOn-Site Infrared TrainingInfrared ServicesInfrared ConsultingEMT Training EMT CoursesEMT Training ScheduleLive EMT Webcasts & On-Demand WebinarsOn-Site EMT TrainingEMT ServicesEMT Consulting
Tweets by TheSnellGroup
HomePrivacy Policy Privacy Policy
Print This PageThis privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used on our website, online transactions, and newsletters. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.Quick LinksWho we are?What information do we collect?How do we use personal information?How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?What legal basis do we have for processing your personal data?When do we share personal data?Where do we store and process personal data?How do we secure personal data?Use of cookies and other technologiesLinking to other websites / third party contentCalifornia Online Privacy Protection ActCOPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)Fair Information PracticesCAN SPAM ActYour rights in relation to personal dataHow to contact us?Who we are?If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.The Snell Group322 N Main StBarre, Vermont 05641United Statesinfo@thesnellgroup.comWhat information do we collect?When appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, or other details to help you with your experience when:Completing Online TransactionsPayPal: External PCI compliant payment gateway (Privacy Policy)Downloading White PapersRegistering for Online CoursesLitmos: Online learning management software (Privacy Policy)Signing up for GiveawaysSigning up for NewslettersMailChimp: Email management service (Privacy Policy)Using other website formsHow do we use personal information?Service and business related purposes in which we will process data:Personalisation of website content, business information or user experienceDelivering marketing and events communicationCarrying out polls and surveysInternal research and development purposesProviding goods and servicesLegal obligations (eg prevention of fraud)Meeting internal audit requirementsHow does our site handle Do Not Track signals?We honor “Do Not Track” signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a “Do Not Track” (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.What legal basis do we have for processing your personal data?Below are the relevant processing conditions for The Snell Group to process personal data:Consent: When voluntarily downloading White Papers, signing up for Newsletters, signing up for Giveaways, or using other website forms. Individuals can withdraw and manage their consent by contacting us or by managing their Newsletter subscription preferences in the footer of our Newsletters. Legitimate Interests: When completing online transactions and registering for Online Courses.When do we share personal data?The Snell Group treats personal data confidentially and does not release, sell, or otherwise distribute the personal information of our customers to others, except by court order.Where do we store and process personal data?We store and process data at The Snell Group’s US headquarters in Barre, Vermont:The Snell Group322 N Main StBarre, Vermont 05641United Statesinfo@thesnellgroup.comHow do we secure personal data?Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order, enters, or submits their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.We use regular Malware ScanningUse of cookies and other technologiesCookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We use cookies to:Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future.You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. Typically you do this through your browser settings. Since all browsers are a little different, look at your browser's Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. Note: If you turn cookies off, it won't affect your experience.Google AnalyticsTo opt out of Google Analytics users can use the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on or by declining to use cookies when notified upon visiting our website.Linking to other websites / third party contentAt times we may link to external sites and resources from our website through social media feeds or other content. This does not constitute endorsement, and we take no responsibility for the content (or information contained within) any linked website.California Online Privacy Protection ActAccording to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:Users can visit our site anonymously.Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy' and can easily be found on the page specified above.You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:On our Privacy Policy PageCan change your personal information:By emailing usBy calling usOthersMailCOPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control.We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.Fair Information PracticesIn order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:We will notify you via email within 3 business days.CAN SPAM ActWe collect your email address in order to:Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.Send you additional information related to our product and/or service.Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at info@thesnellgroup.com or:Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from correspondence.Your rights in relation to personal dataUnder the GDPR, we respect the right of data subjects to access and control their personal data. If requested we will provide:Correction or deletion of informationData portabilityWithdrawal of consentFor any personal data requests you can contact us directly through the methods listed below.How to contact us?If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices or personal information, you can contact us directly through the methods below:Address: The Snell Group - 322 N Main St Barre, Vermont 05641 (United States)Email: info@thesnellgroup.comPhone: 802-479-7100 or Toll-Free in the US and Canada at 800-636-9820Online: http://www.thesnellgroup.com/contact-us
United States Headquarters322 N Main StSuite 8Barre, Vermont 05641Tel: +1.802.479.7100Fax: +1.802.479.7171Toll-Free: 1.800.636.9820Email: info@thesnellgroup.comUnited States Midwest Office4427 SW Admiral Byrd DriveLee's Summit, MO 64082-8585Tel: +1.802.479.7100Fax: +1.802.479.7171Canada4981 Hwy 7 East, Unit 12ASuite 198Markham, Ontario L3R 1N1Tel: +1.905.508.3305Fax: +1.802.479.7171
